Good luck with that, soldier.
I can smell the Ishbalan stray dog.
But...
he's gone now.
Say, Brother,
what's going to happen to Marcoh-san?
The Führer said he was going to look after him.
What can we do about it?
The Central Library?
Marcoh-san had to hide all of his materials right under the military's nose.
And this...
What do you suppose that means?
I don't know.
In any case, let's keep this a secret from the Colonel and the others.
Brother?
Whether or not we can trust them anymore...
I'm not sure.
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
You're leaving so suddenly?
Mm-hmm. Now that we know that Scar is in East City,
everyone seems to have become
worried about Central all of a sudden.
Sorry to have inconvenienced you,
but we're going back.
Before you do,
what is your punishment?
Punishment?
I knew where the Crystal Alchemist was,
and yet I left him alone.
You've done well.
I wanted to place him in protective custody.
The officer directly underneath me—
Grand—was against it,
but he put his research to use on the battlefield, which must have tormented him.
At this late date, I would like to make it up to him.
However, concerning his research...
That will be all.
I will continue to rely on you.
May you have a safe journey.
The Philosopher's Stone...
does not exist.
As you can see, I'm fine.
You'd probably shape up
if you did get punished once.
He never seems to
let his guard down.
Creation follows destruction!
I shall fix you up nice and pretty!
Th-That's all right...
The method of bonding a soul to armor...
is only known by one person:
Fullmetal.
Yeah, and for that to happen, I first
need to do something about my arm.
You're right. After all, if Edward-kun is unable to use his alchemy...
...he's just a sharp-tongued brat.
Anyhow, I'm going to my mechanic.
Colonel, you know who, right?
Yeah. I saw our good-for-nothing alchemist there once, bawling in pain.
"It hurts! It hurts so bad!
I'm going to pee my pants!" Right?
What are you going to do once you're fixed up?
I'm going to Central.
There's something I want to look up in the library there.
That's going to be a long trip.
Which means...
Since I'm part of the Führer's party, I won't be able to accompany you.
I can't very well leave here.
And I have to
keep an eye on him.
I don't think I'd be able to protect
those two from such a dangerous guy.
That goes for me too!
That settles it, then.
I shall escort these two during their journey!
We don't need that!
What are you going to do if Scar
attacks you again in your condition?
You can't carry Al
like that either, can you?
Children should listen to adults.
Y-You're calling us children?! Al, say something!
Brother! This is the first time anyone has ever treated me like a child since I got this body!
Very well, Edward Elric...
Shall we begin packing?
This is the first time anyone has ever
treated me like luggage since I got this body.
For crying out loud...
Hey, newspaper?
I've got tea as well!
Shoo, shoo!
Hey, I've got a message from Roy.
From the Colonel?
"Don't go dying under my command.
It's a pain having to deal with everything."
That is all.
Tell him, "Roger. There's no way I'm going to die ahead of you, you grubby colonel."
And while you're at it,
take this escort with you, too.
Hey, now...
I don't know what Marcoh told you,
but let me inform you of one thing.
Three years ago,
we discovered the body of a young girl who had been transmuted into a Chimera.
Nina?!
The way she was torn apart...
It turns out to be identical to Scar's method of alchemy.
Thanks, man.
Now I can take him on.
I'll see you in Central. I'll apply for permission to browse at the first branch.
You'll have to excuse me for using my left hand.
Central... Central's first...
first something-or-other!
Central Library, First Branch.
Mm-hmm!
That's enough, right?
Brother!
Sorry about that.
What is the Führer...
What is the Führer's answer?
You told that boy where your materials are hidden, didn't you?
What are you talking about?
That's okay.
The boy will come even closer to the Philosopher's Stone.
However, I would be a little upset
if you wrote down anything extra in those materials.
The boy is smart. Once he reads it, he won't do as you want him to.
Which is why, before he does,
I thought I'd look into it myself, you see?
That won't be possible.
You're going to die...
right here!
That was cruel.
I've already died once, you know.
So that's it!
Just like the stories say,
you guys are...
Gluttony...
Tell me...
Where did you tell the boy you hid your materials?
Whew, I've had it, Al.
That guy just keeps
going on and on,
and all he does is brag about his family background.
Let me take a break here—
Al?
Al? Al? Al? Al? Al?
Al?!
Al got mistaken for someone else's luggage and was dropped off at the last station!
Hm? That won't do. We'll go back for him at the next station.
I can't wait that long!
Now, now...
Stay out of my way!
Calm down, Edward Elric.
What else could I do?
If I, a suit of armor, said "not here," they would just be stunned by me.
I wonder if Brother has noticed.
I'm the one who wants to cry, here!
Uh-oh...
He wouldn't have gone off somewhere by himself!
You're sure...
it was this armor?
Mm-hmm.
You're good at drawing, huh?
It's a technique for drawing likenesses that has been passed down in my family for generations.
How can you be
taking this so lightly?!
Wait, it's too dangerous!
What's the hurry?
You guys just don't understand us!
What?
I heard from Doctor Marcoh!
About what happened in Ishbal!
Say, do you know anything about some armor that was at the train station?
Like who might've taken it?
It was large and dark...
Just a second, please!
Ee-yow...
Hey! Hold it!
Hold on!
Hold on, I tell you!
Damn. If I had my arm and leg, this wouldn't be so hard...
This is trouble... We're getting farther
and farther away from the train station.
Ahem...
Am I hearing things?
I'm right here. This armor.
That didn't hurt at all! With this...
Um...
It's doing it again!
Please don't be startled. I'm...
Um, I'm...
the latest model of armor.
We're popular now in Central. Talking armor.
Where's your switch?! Be quiet!
Um, you can't turn me off.
Just keep quiet, then.
Um, where are we going?
To a fight.
A fight?
Boss Poe said that
if I wanted to be like him,
I should go rub out a guy or two.
So I told him that I would go
lay into the Damousha family,
who are always
invading our territory.
If I bring back one of
their heads like this,
then no one will treat me like a kid anymore.
I'll be accepted as the boss's right-hand-man!
I'll do it! I'll flatten them!
You're not, by any chance, going to go kill someone?
You're some pretty good armor.
I won't even have to worry if they pull a gun on me.
That's why you're wearing me?
So it won't hurt?
That's right. As long as I'm not hurt, I can go all-out.
It's still going to hurt.
What? Are you a defective product?
I'm sure it will hurt.
In your heart.
Don't be silly.
Or would you rather you didn't feel pain in your heart?
Relax your arm.
Wh-What is this?!
I am the Cursed Farmer... I mean,
Nyoroi no Noroi
the Cursed Armor.
Noroi no Yoroi
Once you become one with me,
your mind and body will never
feel pain again, forever and ever.
I'm sorry about this.
Having been made to live alone together with an old man,
she was thinking of what was best for the future, in her own way.
So she was just hoping to make things easier for her grandpa, huh?
You did pretty well
to have noticed this.
I can't give you this,
but if you want, I could introduce you
to the engineer who made it.
She's got a sharp tongue
but decent skills.
I appreciate the offer,
but I don't need an artificial leg.
Once you get used to it,
it's pretty handy.
Perhaps so. However...
However, I'd like to leave my leg the way it is.
A sword wound I received on
the battlefield became infected.
By the time they carried me to the rear, all they could do was cut it off.
Battlefield... You were a soldier?
Which war?
The one up north?
Or...
You don't mean Ishbal?!
On the battlefield,
everyone becomes some other creature.
You can carry out even the most cruel acts without any feeling.
In order to protect myself, my mind must have shut out all emotions.
But once the war is over,
you can't keep doing that.
I must not forget what I saw there...
what I did there.
When I look at this injury, it allows me to remember it all immediately.
And that's why...
That's why you don't want
any Automail?! That isn't very—
That's not the only reason.
I lost my leg.
However, I have gained something even more important.
Peace of mind, and a life with my grandchildren. You see...
It's once a person loses something
that they first gain something, is it not?
You think so?
There are those who've
gone to war and come back fine.
That's what soldiers do.
Those people have lost something.
Even if it isn't something
visible to the eye.
If you've lost something yourself,
then you should've gained something as well.
In alchemy, that is what's known as equivalent exchange, right?
How can that be?!
I lost my right arm and left leg...
and my brother lost his whole body.
We're living desperately just to get them back!
Taking everything back—
that's what our dream is!
There isn't a thing
we've gained in return!
Everything...
has been taken from us!
A dream to take everything back...
But then, once that comes true,
what will you do?
A dream that is granted can't be called a real dream at all.
Even so...
Even so, we're going to take it back.
Thanks for the tea.
Brother!
Grandpa, Brother is home!
Oh, that's right! Al!
Al!
Yes!
Al...
Al,
you reek of sheep.
Well, excuse me! Fine, when we get to
Grandma Pinako's house, I'll get washed up.
Say, Al...
Four years ago, when the Colonel came to Resembool,
he said it was because he happened to look at the letter we sent out, right?
That's what he said.
He was searching for Dad.
But, by any chance, do you think the reason
that the Colonel went to Granny's house was...
Major...
I was worried about you.
Sorry about that.
What's wrong?
Major...
I'm sorry about earlier...
Oh, no!
If we miss this one, we'll have to wait until tomorrow at noon!
H-Hey! What are you doing?!
We're going to run!
This is the method of
short-distance sprinting
that has been passed down
through my family for generations!
Put me down!
I'm going to break!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 17: "House of the Waiting Family"
On the day we left,
we burned down our house.
We had nowhere to return home to.
Or so we thought...